A Finding Aid to the Emily A. Francis papers, circa 1910s-1969, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Emily A. Francis papers
circa 1910s-1969
Archives of American Art
Francis, Emily A., 1879-1966
AAA.franemil
Archival Resource Key
10 Linear feet
The Emily A. Francis papers, circa 1910s-1969, measure 10 linear feet and include organizational records of Contemporary Arts and affiliated member organization, Collectors of American Art, Inc., founded and directed by Emily A. Francis in 1929 and 1937, respectively. The collection consists of biographical material, foundation and board materials, correspondence, artist files, gallery files, exhibition files, membership materials, business and financial material, printed material, scrapbooks, artwork, and photographs.
Biographical / Historical
Emily A. Francis (1879-1966) (also known as Emily Jacobs) was the director of the Contemporary Arts gallery (also known as Contemporary Arts, Inc.) in New York, which she founded in 1929 and incorporated into a membership organization in 1931.
Inspired by the American Art-Union (1839-1851), she organized the Collectors of American Art, Inc. in 1937, which was associated with the gallery and initially called the Painting of the Month Club. Contemporary Arts held group shows and selected original artist prints and paintings to distribute annually to Collectors of American Art, Inc. paying members, which began at $5.00 per year. The stated mission of Collectors of American Art, Inc. was "to encourage production and distribution of Fine Art in America." Contemporary Arts sponsored painters and sculptors and exhibited their works in annual traveling exhibitions to universities and art centers across the country, as well as internationally; held regular Monday evening open house receptions for artists to exhibit their paintings and sculptures and chat with the public; and held monthly "Meet the Artist" parties for high schoolers to talk with the artists. Francis was born in Christchurch, New Zealand, and first visited the United States in 1913, emigrating in 1916. She remained director of Contemporary Arts and Collectors of American Art, Inc. until her death in New York City in 1966, at the age of 87.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 12 series.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1921-1966 (0.1 linear feet; Box 1)
Series 2: Foundation and Board Materials, 1928-1969 (0.6 linear feet; Box 1)
Series 3: Correspondence, 1924-1964 (1.9 linear feet; Boxes 1-3)
Series 4: Artist Files, 1933-1964 (0.3 linear feet; Box 3)
Series 5: Contemporary Arts Gallery Files, 1930-1966, undated (1.1 linear feet; Boxes 3-4)
Series 6: Exhibition Files, 1931-1965 (0.8 linear feet; Box 5)
Series 7: Membership Materials, 1935-1966, undated (0.4 linear feet; Boxes 5-6)
Series 8: Business and Financial Material, 1928-1966 (1.3 linear feet; Boxes 6-7)
Series 9: Printed Material, 1931-1966, undated (Boxes 7-8)
Series 10: Scrapbooks, 1931-1962 (1.2 linear feet; Box 8-9, 13-14)
Series 11: Artwork, 1940-1962, undated (0.9 linear feet; Boxes 10-12)
Series 12: Photographs, circa 1910s - circa 1960s (0.1 linear feet; Boxes 10, 12)
Scope and Contents
The Emily A. Francis papers, circa 1910s-1969, measure 10 linear feet and include organizational records of Contemporary Arts and affiliated member organization, Collectors of American Art, Inc., founded and directed by Emily A. Francis in 1929 and 1937, respectively. The collection consists of biographical material, foundation and board materials, correspondence, artist files, gallery files, exhibition files, membership materials, business and financial material, printed material, scrapbooks, artwork, and photographs.
Biographical materials include personal financial material and documents relating to Francis' emigration from New Zealand in 1916. Foundation and board materials document the founding and continuing business of Contemporary Arts and Collectors of American Art, Inc. through board books, meetings minutes, by-laws, and articles of incorporation. Correspondence is with New York and international artists, as well as members, institutions, galleries, and board members; and artist files consist of correspondence, scattered photographs, exhibition materials, and consignment and loan agreements. Among the artists featured extensively in correspondence and artist files are Edward Betts, Virginia Cuthbert, Charles Logasa, and Sam Middleton.
Contemporary Arts gallery files document gallery activities through consignment and loan files to institutions and galleries, inventory records, sign-in registers, and event files. Exhibition files include loan agreements, exhibition price lists, and exhibition catalog mock-ups, as well as scattered correspondence. The files also include membership registers, member bulletin mock-ups, and other membership files, as well as financial ledgers with sales and artist accounts, leases and legal documents, receipts and invoices, and other business and financial material. Exhibition announcements and catalogs, member bulletins and annual reports, "The Bulletin of the Collectors of American Art, Inc.," and other printed material, are also included. Fifteen scrapbooks contain clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs relating to Contemporary Arts and Collectors of American Art, Inc. Extensive artwork consists of a charcoal sketch, paintings and paint sketches, and original prints, including woodcuts and serigraphs. Photographs are of Emily A. Francis and others, gallery installation views, events, and artwork.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. Access to original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated in 1965 by Emily A. Francis and in 2023 by Peter Van Doren, a client of Francis.
Existence and Location of Copies
Portions of the collection are available on 35mm microfilm reels D224-D226 & D232-D233 available at Archives of American Art offices and through interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the arrangement of material described in the finding aid does not reflect the arrangement of the collection on microfilm.
Scrapbooks; Gallery directors -- New York (State) -- New York; Women art dealers; Bishop, Isabel, 1902-1988; Lazzari, Pietro, 1898-1979; Logasa, Charles, 1883-1936; Mayer, Grace M.; Middleton, Samuel M., 1927-; Wilson, Ellis, 1899-1977; Contemporary Arts (Gallery); Collectors of American Art (Firm)
- Biographical Material, 1921-1966; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 0.1 Linear feet Box 1
  Scope and Contents
  Biographical materials include documents relating to Emily A. Francis' emigration from New Zealand; personal financial and legal material; professional letters of reference and job search materials; correspondence and documents regarding the financial trust of her mother Emily Rose Jacobs; artist-signed Christmas letter; and biographical sketches and obituary clippings.
  - Artist-Signed Christmas Letter, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Clippings and Portrait Photograph, circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Biographical Sketch, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letter of Congratulations and Anniversary Invitations, circa 1956-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters of Reference and Job Search Document, circa 1926; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - New Zealand Birth Record and U.S. Naturalization Certificate, 1921, 1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Personal Financial and Legal Material, 1929-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Tax Returns, 1924-1925; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Will, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Emily Rose Jacobs Trust Materials, 1927-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Obituaries (Emily A. Francis and Emily Rose Jacobs), 1926, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Foundation and Board Materials, 1928-1969; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 0.6 Linear feet Box 1
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged as two subseries.
  2.1 Contemporary Arts, 1928-1969
  2.2 Collectors of American Art, Inc., 1938-1966
  Foundation and Board Materials are divided into two subseries. The first subseries includes board of directors meeting minutes, board books, board reports, certificate of incorporation, and other board documents for Contemporary Arts. The second subseries consists of by-laws, certificates of incorporation, board of directors meeting minutes, board books, board reports, draft board letters, distribution lists, committee reports, and materials relating to the Collectors of American Art, Inc.
  - Contemporary Arts, 1928-1969; 2.1; Archival Resource Key
    - Board Book, Minutes and Charter Members List, 1928-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1931-1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1955-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1960, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Board Report, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Certificate of Incorporation, 1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Plans and Objectives for Contemporary Arts, Inc., 1966-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Collectors of American Art, Inc., 1938-1966; 2.2; Archival Resource Key
    - Board Letters and Drafts, 1955-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Board Book, By-Laws and Meeting Minutes, 1951-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1938-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Board of Directors Minute Book, 1939-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Board of Directors Minute Book, 1951-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Board of Directors Minute Book, 1957-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
    - Board Proposals and Meeting Notes, 1965-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - By-Laws, 1938-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Certificates of Incorporation, 1937-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Information About Collectors of American Art, Inc., 1938-circa 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Lists of Prints Distributed, 1940-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Nominating Committee Report and Proxy Forms, 1961-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Plan for Corporate Sponsors and Membership, 1948-1953, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Social Welfare Law Consent Forms, 1954-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1938-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 35-36)
- Correspondence, circa 1924-circa 1969; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 1.9 Linear feet Boxes 1-3
  Correspondence is with artists, including Edward Betts, Isabel Bishop, Louis Bosa, Virginia Cuthbert, Emma Ehrenreich, Roger Holt, Pietro Lazzari, Lawrence Lebduska, Charles Logasa, Alden Mason, Grace Mayer, Sam Middleton, Elliot Orr, Sadie Rosenblum, Stanley Twardowicz, Ellis Wilson, as well as Collectors of American Art, Inc. members, institutions and galleries, board members, and others. Emily A. Francis' personal correspondence is also included.
  - Archives of American Art, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Edward Betts, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Isabel Bishop, circa 1939-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Virginia Cuthbert, circa 1945- circa 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 40-42)
  - Winslow Eaves, 1948-circa 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Cathya P. Farquhar (Mrs. Percival Farquhar), 1943-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Joseph Gualtieri, 1951-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Clare J. Hoffman, Inc., 1951-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 46-47)
  - Hollis Holbrook, 1953-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Roger Holt, 1948-circa 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 49)
    Includes illustrated letter.
  - Murray Jones, 1951-circa 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Florence Kawa, 1946-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Sigmund Kozlow, 1946-circa 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Pietro Lazzari, 1943-circa 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Lawrence H. Lebduska, 1924-1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 54)
    Includes photograph of artist.
  - Lawrence H. Lebduska, 1938-circa 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Charles Logasa, 1931-circa 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Includes illustrated letters.
  - Alden C. Mason, 1954-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Grace Mayer, 1938-circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Sam Middleton, 1959-circa 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - Susan Moore, 1950-circa 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Jack Selid Morganrath, 1949-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Sam Morland, 1951-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Phillip Pieck, 1943-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 10-14)
  - Walter H. Stevens, 1959-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - William Story, 1956-circa 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Stanley Twardowicz, 1947-circa 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Martha Visser't Hooft, 1946-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
  - Ellis Wilson, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Includes photographs of artwork.
  - Collectors of American Art, Inc. Board Correspondence, 1954-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 21-23)
  - Collectors of American Art, Inc. Member Correspondence, 1952-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 24-26)
  - Contemporary Arts, A-B, 1955-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Contemporary Arts, C, 1955-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Painting of the Month Club, 1935-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Personal Correspondence, Emily A. Francis, 1930-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - General Correspondence, 1930-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 31)
    Includes Bartlett Arkell and Eliot Orr.
  - General Correspondence, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 32-33)
    Includes Bernadine Custer.
  - General Correspondence, 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 34)
    Includes Florence Brillinger and Theodora Kane.
  - General Correspondence, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 35)
    Includes Eugene Higgins and Peggy Bacon.
  - General Correspondence, 1940-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 36-37)
    Includes Louis Bosa, Eliot Orr, and Etienne Ret.
  - General Correspondence, 1946-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 38-43)
    Folder 38 includes Harold Baumbach and Gerard Hordijk.
  - General Correspondence, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 44)
    Includes inquiry card from Hughie Lee-Smith.
  - General Correspondence, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 45)
    Includes Vincent Hartgen and Emmanuel Viviano.
  - General Correspondence, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    Includes William H. Littlefield, Guy Maccoy, Sadie Rosenblum, and Emmanuel Viviano.
  - General Correspondence, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 3-5)
    Includes Arnold Herstand, Gerard Hordijk, William H. Littlefield, and Guy Maccoy.
  - General Correspondence, 1956-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
    Includes Betty Esman, Lena Gurr, Theo Hios, Alden C. Mason, Jeannette Genius McKean, Lowell Naeve, Virginia Paccassi, and Sadie Rosenblum.
  - General Correspondence, 1960-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8-12)
  - General Correspondence, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13-14)
  - General Correspondence, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Includes Guy Maccoy.
  - General Correspondence, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 16-18)
  - General Correspondence, 1965-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19-20)
  - General Correspondence, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Includes illustrated letter by Louis Bosa.
- Artist Files, 1933-circa 1964; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 0.3 Linear feet Box 3
  Artist files include correspondence, scattered photographs, biographical details, and consignment and loan agreements, and exhibition catalogs and announcements for artists represented by Contemporary Arts and/or part of the Collectors of American Art, Inc. Artists include Edward Betts, Bernice Cross, Lawrence Lebduska, Charles Logasa, Sam Middleton, Phillip Pieck, and Stanley Twardowicz, among others.
  - Margit Beck, 1956-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Edward Betts, 1953-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23-24)
  - Willian Chaiken, 1954-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Bernice Cross, 1938-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26)
    Includes original sketches.
  - Stephen Csoka, 1947-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Virginia Cuthbert, 1953-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Nassos Daphnis, 1938-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Emma Ehrenreich, 1953-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Lawrence H. Lebduska, 1937-1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Charles Logasa, circa 1933-1936, circa 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 32-33)
    Includes snapshots, photographs of artwork, and original sketches.
  - Sam Middleton, 1959-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 34-35)
    Includes photographs of artist in studio and artwork.
  - Phillip Pieck, 1946-circa 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 36-37)
  - A.J. Stromsted, 1947-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Stanley Twardowicz, 1948-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Joe Wollins, 1954-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Contemporary Arts Gallery Files, 1930-1966, undated; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 1.1 Linear feet Boxes 3-4
  Contemporary Arts gallery files document gallery activities through loan files with galleries, universites, and museums; consignment agreements; inventory records and ledger; two sign-in books; and publicity and event files. Loan institutions include Albright Art Gallery, Art Institute of Chicago, Brooklyn Museum, Carnegie Institute, George Walter Vincent Smith Art Gallery, M. H. de Young Memorial Museum, Museum of Modern Art, and Whitney Museum of American Art, among others.
  - Artist Biographies, 1937-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 41-42)
  - Consignments Delivered and Received, 1935-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Donation Acknowledgements from Foundations, 1961-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Event, 25th Anniversary Dinner, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Event Sign ("Theatre Benefit for Contemporary Arts"), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Gallery Lecture Typescripts by Emily A. Francis and Others, 1930-1952, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Gallery Plan/Layout, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Inventory Ledger, 1945-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5-7)
  - Inventory Received and Returned, 1963-1965, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
  - Letterhead and Consignment Form, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Lists, Inventory, Loans, Prices, 1937-1955, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Lists of Works Insured for Traveling Exhibitions, 1948-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Loans, Addison Gallery of Art, 1938-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Loans, Albright Art Gallery, 1938-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Loans, American Federation of Arts, 1938, 1945-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Loans, Art Institute of Chicago, 1939-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Loans, Brooklyn Museum, 1939-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Loans, Bucknell University, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Loans, Carnegie Institute, 1943-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19-20)
  - Loans, Clearwater Art Museum, 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Loans, Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1943, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Loans, Dayton Art Institute, 1953-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Loans, Denver Art Museum, 1954-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Loans, Fabry Associates, 1954-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Loans, George Walter Vincent Smith Art Gallery, 1938-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Loans, Gross Art Center, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Loans, Indiana University, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Loans, M.H. de Young Memorial Museum, 1942-1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Loans, Minnesota State Fair, 1944-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Loans, Montclair Art Museum, 1939-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Loans, Museum of Modern Art, 1942-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Loans, Netherlands Information Bureau, 1944-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Loans, Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, 1938-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Loans, Portland Museum, 1940-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Loans, Rhode Island School of Design Museum of Art, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Loans, Roadside Furniture Shops, Inc., 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Loans, San Joaquin Pioneer Museum, 1953-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Loans, Springfield Museum of Fine Arts, 1941-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Loans, Stanford University, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Loans, State University of Iowa, 1946-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Loans, Stuart Art Gallery, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Loans, Syracuse Museum of Fine Arts, 1941-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Loans, Toledo Musem of Art, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Loans, Tomorrow's Masterpieces, Inc., 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Loans, University of Nebraska Department of Art, 1944-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Loans, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1944-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Loans, Whitney Museum of American Art, 1943-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Loans, Worcester Art Museum, 1940-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Loans, Miscellaneous, 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Loans, Miscellaneous, 1938-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 51-55)
  - Loans, Miscellaneous, 1950-1965, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 56-59)
  - Mailing Lists, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - "Meet the Artists", 1950-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Publicity, 1949, 1960, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Relocation of Gallery, 1953-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Sign-In Book, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Sign-In and Member Interest Ledger, circa 1931-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 65)
- Exhibition Files, 1931-1965; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 0.8 Linear feet Box 5